Hello, George.
Hello.
How you doing, man?
Good.
How was Greece?
Very nice.
Where'd you go?
Greece and Rafina.
And where?
Rafina.
That's an interesting place to go.
Yeah, because my cousins have an apartment there.
Ah, okay.
When I was a kid, Rafina was very far away from Athens because it hadn't been built out until there.
Right.
So when I was a kid, Rafina was always I always thought of Rafina as very far away because that's where my family in downtown Athens would go for the summer.
Yeah.
Right.
And it was a bit of an adventure back then because they didn't have a car, so we'd have to take the bus.
I took the bus once to Athens.
It took like an hour.
Yeah, but this is like, you know, back in the day, right?
So we would arrive there and we would go swimming, right?
That was where we would go swimming for the summer.
So when I turned so I did my first marathon ten years ago, ten, twelve years ago.
And I'm yes, I have joined.
And Nick's on the wrong Zoom.
So we arrived in Athens.
Am I?
I arrive.
Hello, Nicholas.
Hey, no problem now.
So I arrive in Athens.
So we would arrive there.
I was telling the story, I arrived to do my marathon.
So I show up in Athens and I get the map, right, for the Athens Marathon.
And I hadn't actually looked at the distance up until that time, right?
I trained for the marathon, but I didn't actually look, you know, 42 kilometers is a large distance, but you don't realize how big it is.
And so I'm looking at the map and I realize that Marathon is 10 kilometers away from Rafina, which in my mind was already very far away.
Yeah.
I was like, holy fuck, what am I doing?
You started in Athens and you finish in Rafina.
No, no, you start in Marathon, which is 10 kilometers.
Oh, you do the whole thing?
Yeah, I did the whole marathon, right?
So you start in Marathon, right?
And there's actually a detour to go see where they buried the dead from the Battle of Marathon, right?
So you start in Marathon, you take a left, do the detour, go to the beach, and then go back.
And it's a crazy, if you're going to ever do a marathon, I recommend it because it's a very fun marathon.
You start off in the hinterland of Tiki, right?
Past Pastrafina, past everything.
You go through farmland, and then you start climbing, and then you get into downtown Athens.
And then there's like a 10-kilometer downhill until you hit Kolonaki.
And you finish in the stadium where the first marathon, the first modern marathon finished.
Not too hot?
It's in November.
So November.
Yeah, so two points.
It can be brutally hot.
One year I did it, and it was like I almost died of a heart attack.
But the other years it was so cold that people were freezing.
So it depends.
But in general, it's actually quite pleasant.
My favorite marathon story is: there's this couple, they were about my age now, but they were a little bit older than me, and they're on their phone talking to their son.
They took a break and they're talking to their son who finished, who was competing in the national team in the Athens Marathon.
They're talking to him about how did he do it?
We're like three, four hours away from finished, and they're talking to their son who finished like finished.
And I'm like, that is quit this edge with Greek parents.
Try to do one in 10 years.
What?
Dude, you should totally do one.
It's like the three of you should do one.
Nicholas goes, yeah, I'm not that stupid.
My friend did one like a week ago just to like do his cardio.
Really?
And Montreal.
He's started running.
He started.
Did he do the full marathon or?
Yeah, 42K.
Shit.
How old is he?
Here's my age.
17?
You're 17 or 18?
Actually, he's 16.
I'm 17.
All right.
Because in Greece, they don't let you do it until they don't actually let you in the U.S.
register until you're 18.
No, it wasn't an official marathon.
You just did it by himself.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
I was going to say, that's why I asked, because they can, yeah, no, totally.
And they don't, because of liability, they don't let people do it.
They don't want to deal with not the liability of people getting hurt, but the liability of having underage kids running in a race with lots of adults in an unsupervised manner.
So people are like, the guy, the organizers, don't want to deal with that.
Because, you know, all it takes is one kid to have something bad happen, and all hell breaks loose.
As you probably know.
All right.
So, first of all, it's great to be back on my favorite campaign ever.
Like, I never really thought this would be, I would have, is it this much fun?
Okay, so a couple things.
You are, let me just, so I did something hopefully that you'll find interesting.
So I wrote, I had, I admit it, I had AI.
You should see it.
Do you see it?
Enroll 20?
Do you see?
You should see the ledger of outstanding business.
Logged in.
Yeah, so if you log in, you'll see it.
I'll see it.
Oh, here.
Yeah.
You see it?
Yes.
George, I don't think you're yet on Rule 20 if you can get there.
Man, why did your computer, man, is so slow?
Thomas, why do you not help your brother?
She has a new laptop.
You should use it.
George, do you use your new laptop or do you still use your old laptop?
I'm using my desktop.
Nick, were you able to get in?
Yeah.
I mean, the thing in the middle, the ledger of outstanding business, like the light is completely down.
Well, okay, so just so you know, I have that's the, if you click on the, there's a Google Doc link at the very top.
I will put the Google Doc link.
Here we go.
I'll put the Google Doc link in the chat so that you guys have it as well.
Let me just do that as well.
Okay.
It's the conceit is that I had AI write it as if it was Zephyr keeping track of notes.
So it basically goes through all the things that you guys have done and tells you what's going on, what quests you have,
so that you kind of tells you, you know, the ledger of outstanding business kept by Zephyr, chief of operations, the obsidiate edge, because somebody has to, and the cleric has declared bookkeeping beneath him.
So.
It's using the notebook LM?
No, no, I've got a whole pipeline of, I'm happy to talk to you guys about it afterwards, but I have a whole technical pipeline for this.
It's a notebook LM was the starting point of me building a whole friggin flamer.
So the important point is owed to management
and finished business down here in our own business and things nobody's paying for us.
Kind of give you a feel for what's going on.
And I will just go to Genome Assistant and read you the short summary of what was going on and we'll jump in.
All right.
But this should keep, this should give you an idea of what all the open quests.
If there's something wrong, it's remember, Zephyr takes bad notes.
That's my in-content.
That's my in-canon way of saying: if there's a mistake, AI, and AI hallucinated, tell me, and blame Zephyr.
These are Zephyr.
Alright.
The party escaped from the fall of the Hall of Ferdegree proved the party's escape from the Hall of Verdigris proved both harrowing and revealing.
After Zephyr was lured by the mental suggestion into acidic, sentient pool, Zinnia leapt in without hesitation to drag him free, while Sequioa made the same mistake twice before scrambling clear.
Calmer deduced that the entity in the water could plant thoughts in their minds, a fact made more sinister when the party later raided Brother Elric's Vane's chambers and discovered his ritual texts strongly implied he had always known about the pool's living nature.
They stripped his quarter of scrolls, ritual texts on elemental water, a bronze mace, a golden pearl ring, and potions of water breathing, leaving Vane with a pointed warning before returning to their lair to rest.
There, Calmer formalized the group's new hierarchy, appointing Zinnia to lead intelligence, Zephyr to manage day-to-day operations, and Sequioa to handle valuables, while declaring spiritual matters as a sole concern.
The rest was interrupted by the arrival of Lucius Graham, a cheerful middleman sent by Barkinar, bearing fine wine, healing potions, and a chest of enchanted goods.
Sequioa and Zephyr each acquired enchanted blades, though the most coveted money items remained out of reach, giving you sharp motivation to plunder deeper into the temple.
Armed with the knowledge that the trolls could be only permanently killed by fire, the party recruited Vorokal, a fire salamander who communicated through their sentient sword frostband and set out to clear the troll here.
After bypassing a chained Albert, they wisely chose to leave alone.
Sequioa and Zephyr launched a devastating surprise assault on two trolls feasting on fallen soldiers.
The fight turned brutal when one troll sprouted extra limbs and left Sequioa gravely wounded.
But Vorokal's searing heat aura denied the treachers their regeneration and turned the tide.
Pressing further through a secret door, Zinnia discovered the party found the troll chieftain's grotesque chamber, walls plastered with filt and bones, furniture built from skeleton remains, and executed a faultless coordinate strike, with Zephyr tripping the massive creature and Sequioa killing it in a single, perfectly placed blow before it could react.
The chieftain's horde yielded gold, platinum, a ring of fire resistance, a healing potion, and a magical wood totem that permanently turned a nearby desk vivid pink.
Alright, so you have a token that changes color.
Pushing onward, Calmer bluffed 20 bold pieces out of a group of air temple bugbears who had quietly claimed former water temple territory.
And the session ended with the party stepping into a ruined reception hall, only for Sequioa to realize with cold certainty that the decorated Minotaur seated on the central throne was very much alive.
Alrighty.
Let me just do one thing.
Is this something going on here?
Oh, yeah,
all right.
Okay.
Alrighty.
And then I hope you guys get if you guys find the summary useful, I hope you find it useful.
I will create the where's the summary?
No, no, the oh, the the the summary.
I'll send you a link to the summary.
It's not my perfectly generated one, so but it's good enough.
It's got some spelling mistakes.
All right, I'll just send it here.
I put it there.
I put it in the chat.
Alright.
And it's got a few errors.
I haven't had a chance to clean everything up.
I was too busy fixing my pipeline.
Alright.
Alrighty.
Facing the Minotaur.
Hello?
Okie dokie.
Alright.
So you've discovered there is a Minotaur here.
Just to remind you, what it says.
Just to remind you of the description.
This 40 by 50 foot chamber was evidently one in which new arrivals were hoisted to the delights of the temple.
At least this is what the wall murals depict.
A few pieces of battered furniture, couches, chairs, and stands remain along the walls.
In the center of a room is a shallow pool.
Its fountains apparently stopped and decorative stopped.
And that means that it's not pouring.
And the decorative statue of a Minotaur sitting on a throne, much dirtied.
Several skeletons lie about the place, and some odd skulls and bones as well, mostly humans, but some humanoids as well.
None of them, none of the many crescents and wall sconces are lit.
No torches remain.
So the only light is the light that you guys are bringing into your room, into the room.
All right.
Okay.
So, what would you, Sequioa?
You've discovered that it's a Minotaur.
The Minotaur has not yet seen you.
What would you like to do?
Get back to people.
All right.
Well, you kind of peeked through the door and saw that he was alive.
So you kind of noticed it before he noticed you.
So you close the door behind you.
The Minotaur still has not noticed you.
You have a couple of choices.
Remember, you're the big bosses at the end of the game.
So nominally, this guy now works for you, or you could kill him and take his treasure.
He works for us.
I said nominally.
Remember, these are chaotic evil creatures.
And does he speak common?
He speaks Abyssal, which I believe you speak.
Yeah, I speak Abyssal.
All right.
No, I speak under Common.
Don't speak Abyssal?
No.
All right.
Does anybody have Calmer have comprehend languages?
Oh, you know who speaks Abyssal?
I bet the fire salamander.
Can we leave the room and come back?
Yeah, I mean, so anyway, so that
let me just see what.
No, he doesn't speak Abyssal either.
So nobody, no, but you know, maybe you could sort of sign yourselves away there.
I mean, it's up to you guys.
Like, how would you like to handle it?
All right, I'll tell him or your boss.
Do you want to bring Calmer in front, dressed as the Earth Clerk?
Yeah.
I'll show him also boss.
You're going to say, okay.
So, Sequioa, you all good with this plan?
All right.
Let me just see what.
Let me just.
Okay.
So you walk in with Calmer, right?
And you announce you're the boss, right?
Turns out the Minotaur really hates the leadership of this place
and is kind of enraged.
So you'll either have to kill it or try to beat it down a little bit and try to talk some sense into it.
So we will roll for initiative first.
Let's just do that.
11.
All right.
24.
So Zinnia 24.
Sequioa 11.
Zephyr.
Sorry.
21.
Calmer.
Just use Calmer's default rule because I mean
Palmer 9.
All right.
Okay.
I don't forget his initiative.
All right.
Let me just do this, guys.
It's a 10.
Descending.
All right.
No.
Let's see if he surprises you.
It's his stealth.
Is he a stealth?
He's got a very bad stealth.
All right.
Is anybody's passive perception below 15?
Below down.
You're below eight?
That's your passive perception?
No, I'm at 11.
All right.
So what about you, Sequioa?
My passive perception is 16.
No, not wrong, not 16.
Sorry.
10.
All right.
What about you, Zephyr?
17.
I rolled initiative on the wrong character sheets.
All right.
11 still.
Okay, well, nothing changed.
By the way, by the way, if you guys want to help me, when you click your character and then click initiative, it automatically adds it to the intern order.
So if you hit the DND beyond, when you click your character and then click the DND Beyond Initiative button, it'll automatically do that.
It'll save us some time.
Just keep that in mind.
If you don't remember, no big deal.
I can still manually do it.
All right.
So, Zephyr and Sequioa are surprised.
Calmer and Zinnia are not.
The Minotaur attacks Zephyr.
Why?
Because Zephyr announced that he was the boss.
All right.
Okay.
So does he move 10 feet?
Yes, he moves 10 feet from here to here.
Just measure.
Yes, it's definitely 10 feet.
It's definitely 10 feet.
Okay, then it hits you with its gore attack.
All right.
And it's going to roll it recklessly.
So, which means it looks except I did not roll correctly.
And let me just make this public.
Okay.
All right.
So.
Okay.
So RD RD.
24.
That is a hit.
All right.
You take
seven points of damage.
Wow, that was pretty bad.
That was really, really bad.
And then you take, like, why did I even bother rolling that?
Another 10 points of damage.
And you must succeed.
Roll a DC 14 saving throw.
Because of what?
Texas are strength.
One.
You rolled one.
All right.
So you are knocked prone.
You are knocked against here.
And you are prone.
All right.
He moves there to.
That's his reach.
All right.
He moves there to keep beating you because he hates you so much.
Because he hates the management here.
All right.
Zephyr, you were surprised.
Sequioa, you were surprised.
Zinnia, you're up.
Yeah, yeah.
I'll attack it.
What does it cost?
19.
Shit.
I do 12 points of damage.
All right.
Sounds good.
I miss.
You miss.
Yeah.
All right.
12 points of damage.
Yeah.
All right.
Could you move your guy to where you're located?
Where am I?
You should.
You should be down here.
Okay.
Like, just place him where you are.
You can just play some here if you want.
Slowly again.
All right.
We'll put him over here.
We'll put you over here so that gives Sequioa a chance to move into attack.
All right.
Calmer is also not surprised.
What does Calmer do?
What do you want Calmer to do?
Do you want him to try to talk to this guy or beat him down a little bit before you guys talk to him?
He turns to Zinnia as this head of secret of secret operations.
What should he do?
Zinnia, Calmer needs some advice.
Should he try to kill this creature or talk to him?
I think talking would be.
Let's talk to Nan.
All right.
So you will.
Let me just, do you want me to talk?
All right.
So we will talk.
All right, let me see what his persuasion is.
You rolled.
Intimidation or persuasion?
Want to go with the persuasion?
Sure.
All right.
Yeah.
What did he roll?
Oh, he rolls a 21.
All right.
The creature
stares at Calmer and like with his axe still ready to hit him and points to Zephyr with a clear indication that he views Zephyr as eating material.
Just protect me.
What?
Protect me, please.
Okay.
Okay, so he's willing to negotiate.
So.
Hold on, let me get.
There's a dog that needs something.
Give me a sec.
The anxiety level was off the road by no memor.
All right.
Zinnia, you're up.
So, do you want to.
So the creature might be willing to listen if you can make him an offer.
You, you, you're up now.
Yes.
Colmer got him to like pause before he started relentlessly trying to kill him.
So you, Zephyr, and Sequioa could try to make him an offer.
I'll give you guys.
You can use your actions to try to persuade, intimidate.
I have a bad persuasion.
And I have bad persuasion and intimidation.
All right.
So what you could do is you could try to get Zephyr, what's your persuasion or intimidation?
My persuasion is plus 11 and intimidation.
So you're going to try to, you're going to help him.
You're going to help him, so he has advantage?
Yeah.
All right.
Zephyr.
You're prone.
You've got a creature with a double-headed axe standing over you, sort of, you know, you're Cretan, like standing there ready to and looking at you very hungry.
Are you going to try to persuade it that there's new management?
Are you going to try to tell it?
Yes.
Like, okay, you're going to try to persuade it, new management?
You're different.
You're different?
Oh, my God.
Do I have advantage?
Yeah, you do.
21.
All right.
The creature is wary and looks at you.
Well,
look, we will leave you here.
You will get your.
I don't know.
Don't I see humans?
He eats.
What does a monitor?
Well, what does a minotaur eat?
Generally, a minotaur eats sacrifices from Athens, but in the absence of Atisac.
What does he do?
Exactly.
Okay, what does a minotaur do?
So the minotaur, so the minotaur, now that he's sort of calmed down, you guys, you guys give it some food from your backpacks?
Yeah.
All right.
He starts to eat the food.
Finally, he calms down just enough, like he right and goes.
What does he do?
He says, Bandits, men in black cloaks, come here and attack Minotaur.
This will stop.
We'll stop.
All alone.
Good.
He pauses.
He looks at you, Zephyr, and says, No hard feelings.
No hard feeling.
He goes, Well, this is now my room.
I stand guard.
As long as food keeps coming.
And no more bandit come and attack.
Okay.
But he pauses.
If bandit come attack, I find you, I kill you, I eat you.
Yes.
Promise.
You promise?
No.
Calmer, of course, steps in and says, I don't mean to be rude or anything.
Calmer's going to ask for something.
You're going to have to have to convince him to not ask for it, or you're going to have to see what happens.
I'll bring Convert to my side.
Don't ask for anything.
But I'm in charge here.
I need to make sure that he understands the new rulership arrangements, that there's a new high cleric.
Yes, but he is not very smart, and he will want to eat us.
So I think it's harder to let it be.
Okay, but are you sure?
I will tell him on my own time.
All right, as long as you make sure to make absolutely sure that he knows that there is a new clerical order with the high Lord Master Calmer.
You will?
Okay, excellent.
And by the way, where do you intend to find bodies for this creature?
Probably a bunch left over from the battles.
We'll bring some people into the cult, into the temple, the wander on.
Oh, I see.
We're going to bring sacrifices for the Minotaur.
Excellent.
I think that's a fantastic idea.
Zinnia, roll an insight check.
Insight.
Yeah, that's a very weird thing for a cleric of St.
Cuthbert to say.
Saint Cuthbert, just so you know, is a fanatically one of those gods that's very lawful good.
What?
Calmer, are you feeling okay?
Yes, why wouldn't I be feeling okay?
I'm absolutely.
It's just enjoying my new role as high cleric of the Temple of Earth.
Do you know how much he pauses and goes, you know, I started off as a cleric of St.
Cuthbert, and I'm still very much, and I understand, you know, St.
Cuthbert promised me all these things.
What did I get?
I got killed.
And who saved me?
A tiefling.
Not the cleric of, not the high cleric, not my order, but a tiefling, and he looks at you, and a spy with a scarred face, and a rogue.
They were willing to go into my temple and pay the fee to raise me from the dead.
They were willing to sacrifice themselves so that I wouldn't have my body mutilated, so I could be raised for the dead.
It kind of puts a different spin on all the religious doctrine that I've been fed my whole life.
I just, you know, I've come to the realization that loyalty is a two-way street, and you have demonstrated loyalty, and I will demonstrate loyalty to you.
As for St.
Cuthbert and I, we have a good working relationship.
Good.
But there's something to be said about the slavish devotion of evil cultists to their high cleric.
You like it?
Well, like isn't the word I would like to use.
I would simply say that after my experiences with the canon Turjon of Homlet and how he was willing to let me be dead and did nothing to save me, and that the people he dismissed and I'd been raised to dismiss were willing to save my skin simply because I was their ally.
It's kind of put a different perspective on my view on the religious order.
Question.
Well, mullet over.
So, like.
It's not again.
I am not saying that I am all of a sudden an evil, evil cleric of the earth god, but there's something to be said for the material that I've been reading.
It does put a different perspective on the endless prattle of St.
Cuthbert.
Okay.
That's good.
It's good to know.
Okay.
All right.
To the north?
Yes.
Let me just make a note here.
Okay.
So.
So you arrive over here.
There is a.
These guys are no longer here.
Right.
You arrive in this hallway, and let me just make sure.
What do you think so?
Right.
This stairway goes up.
All right.
Can you see that pin, by the way?
Do you see a pin?
Let's say stairway that goes up.
Yeah.
Okay.
Cool.
That's a new feature they added.
Very happy.
All right.
Do you go upstairs or keep looking around?
We came down to consolidate the territory.
Yeah, so presumably you're going to keep going.
You're going to keep looking at the time.
All right.
Okay.
So, okay.
So,
all right.
Okay.
All right.
So you see a door to the south
and a passageway, and you also see the remains of the battle, which is a pile of water and steam.
That's what that blue thing is supposed to indicate.
So, what would you like to do?
There's a passageway going east, north, and I don't think you guys explored the area to the south.
Let's go north.
North?
Yes.
All right.
The one thing you do know is that there is somewhere in the second level, the whatchamacallit, the fire temple, the greater temple has assets.
So you don't know where that is yet.
Just keep that in mind.
Great temple.
Yeah, you know that because when the battle ended, they suddenly showed up from all sorts of locations indicating that they had been here, that they weren't.
There are forces deployed in the second level.
All right.
There's a door to the east and a passageway to the west.
Which way would you like to go?
East.
All right.
Give me one second.
East.
Let's do one thing.
Okay.
East, you said, right?
Yeah.
Yep.
All right.
Okay.
So you open this doorway to the east.
That's 239.
Okay.
This large chamber is evidently used for storing wooden lumber.
Stacks of firewood stand near the entrance.
Planks and beams at several wet sends.
Just inside the entry are large, lumpy sacks.
Apparently, this is a storeroom.
So now you know where you guys store the firewood, which I guess if you're I guess if you're the chief of operations is important.
It's good to know.
Let's go right.
East.
Yep.
Storeroom.
Right.
To the right.
All right.
Okay.
First of all, who can pick the lock?
Sequioa.
Nami.
I can, yeah.
I have these tools.
You have?
All right.
Try to pick the lock.
Will 33 work?
I'm not sure.
Let me check.
Yes, you're able to.
Okay.
You.
All right.
You rolled a 33, right?
Yeah.
All right.
So this is another storeroom.
You're beginning to realize that the temple, you're beginning to realize that the temple is well supplied.
You're also beginning to realize that being the big bad at the end of the game means that you also have to handle supplies and boring things like equipment.
It's not, you know, raping and pillaging and destroying villages and accumulating.
We'll get some other guys to do this.
But you do find a whole bunch of theirs: chainmail armor, plate armor, backpacks, holy water, lanterns, lockpicks, mirrors, parchments, pouches, ropes, sacks, spikes, tinderboxes.
If anybody needs an upgrade in their armor, Calmer doesn't.
Yes.
But
storms.
All right.
And so if you ever need anything like this,
I just put this.
All right.
Okay.
Good to know that the so Zephyr, you've decided you need to hire, you need to put somebody in charge of this.
You know, that's what a good second in command is for?
Yes.
All right.
You know, chief of operations, you're more big ideas, big ideas kind of thing, right?
Let's see.
Okay, let me just see.
Okay.
All right.
So down the hallway.
So one of the things you do remember at this point in time as you're looking at the map, Zephyr, is there's still the three prisoners that are still stuck in over here.
Where?
Yeah, I'm about to do it.
Just make sure I got the right room.
235.
So where was it?
I'm not.
No, I'm sorry.
I take it back.
Prisoners.
Oh, yeah, they were there.
Yep.
Prisoners.
This is where you found one of the prisoners from the Earth Temple, or one of the temples that was supposed to be sacrificed.
You freed one of them, but you haven't freed the other three.
Where are they?
I just put the pin.
Oh, here.
Okay.
You know, just keep that in mind.
Palmer does observe that, you know, we do have a feeding problem.
Feeding problem.
Well, we have a minotaur.
It needs food.
Oh, well.
We have prisoners.
If they're a bad character.
Well, there you go.
So just I just want to point out that we could solve two birds with one stone.
And don't forget, we are now the evil overlords of this temple.
Freeing good people is not exactly something we would be doing.
Are you trying to get your cleric ability taken away?
Or Sequioa, my dear boy, he looks at you and goes, This is a common misconception that the various orthodoxies of the various religions like to present.
But once you reach a certain level of power as a cleric, that power is intrinsic to you as a cleric.
You are not that powerful yet.
Oh, yes, I am.
But have no fear.
It's not my intention.
St.
Cuthbert and I have had a conversation, and we've agreed that my continued integration into the temple is a necessary part of our plans to defeat it.
At this point, Frostband pipes up.
Hey, Sequioa, isn't this what we discussed about our plans here?
That we're going to be sneakity-sneakety?
Yeah, it looks like somebody, though, is forgetting about it.
That's true.
It's like the more days you spend with Calmer as the boss, the more likely bad things happen.
Just keep that in mind.
So we should attack as soon as possible.
Yes, like I'm just saying, like, the more days he spends as the boss, the more he thinks, hmm, maybe being the boss is the good idea.
All right.
Or maybe you need to go outside.
This place evidently held once many stores of supplies.
Much of the foodstuffs are now scattered in ruin, rotting on the table.
Rotting broken containers are tossed about with many mixed temples.
Calmer looks at it, looks at you, Zephyr, and says, Well, I think we'll have to talk to Lucius about cleaning this mess up.
This is absolutely unacceptable.
What?
Oh, here.
Yes.
What's the news?
The Crimson Guard.
Yeah, the Crimson Guard.
You think they're the right ones to have this come?
Yes.
I think so, too.
What's his name?
Do you think Dren Helveth will enjoy this kind of task?
Yeah, he's fond of manual labor.
Very well.
He pauses and thinks.
Perhaps we wish to give each one of these rooms to one of the three clerics.
One to the Earth Temple, one to the Water Temple, one to the Water Temple, one to the Air Temple, and one to the Fire Temple.
That way they goes, I can't count.
Somebody didn't pass school.
Well, yes, I was too busy in my religious learnings.
Did I ever tell you about the problem of St.
Cuthbert's educational systems and the schools that they employ, and the fact that they drill you from the minute you come in into the greatness of St.
Cuthbert?
Oh, yeah.
And how would the Earth Temple fix?
Oh, no.
Oh, that's a great question.
I haven't yet thought about a new educational system based off of the principles of the chaotic temple of Earth.
I've been thinking that perhaps, but that's a great question.
And he pulls out a little piece of scroll and starts scribbling.
We better fill five minutes of silence.
All right.
Okay.
So I'm going to put you guys back in this.
In this area.
Okay.
While this is happening.
Well, this is happening just because
a very large and very disturbingly demented ghoul suddenly sees you as you come down this horror corridor and starts approaching you, moaning.
Zinnia, roll an insight check or investigation with advantage.
I'll do insight.
What if I have an inside sorry?
Okay, I've rolled a one in my first one.
All right.
My second, twelve.
Well, what you remember is that there was a necromancer who was raising the dead.
Remember how all the ghouls showed up?
All right.
And apparently, said Necromancer is still around and active.
And apparently, at Necromancer has upped his game and is no longer just raising minor creatures, but far more deadly creatures.
And so that's what you think about just as the creature decides that, well, you are living.
He is undead.
This is an opportunity.
All right, roll for initiative, gentlemen.
Initiative?
Yes.
Wait, how do you do it inside the roll 20?
So what you do is you click your just click your icon and then click initiative.
That's it.
There's no arrow.
No, no, click inside of DD Beyond initiative as normal.
Just click your icon first.
Huh?
Go into roll 20, click your icon, and then click initiative in DD Beyond.
Okay.
Are you able to get it done?
Did it work?
I see a 21.
Is that your initiative?
No, mine's 19.
All right.
Well, fine.
Didn't work.
That doesn't matter.
All right.
Zinnia, your initiative.
Zinnia, initiative.
George?
Initiative.
I rolled it.
22.
I rolled.
Oh.
He didn't roll.
It didn't show.
No, it did not.
Just tell me the number.
It was 12.
No, it logged me out of Team GPL.
Yeah, it was 12.
All right.
Sequioa, you're up first.
Where is it?
You should sit down to the south.
Ah, there it is.
I do not have enough range to clock get to it, so I'm going to sit here and shoot an arrow at it.
Well, I mean, the other thing you could do is hide and let it come to you.
So I'm just going to poke my head around the corner, shoot an arrow.
All right.
You roll your stealth just to see if you're successfully hide.
Oh, yeah, stealth.
I hit with the torpo and I am hidden.
Oh, yeah, you are definitely hidden.
Now keep in mind, I am at the point.
I have a plus 13 to all the deck stuff.
Okay, so basically, we're just rolling a D1 to see if you rolled a one.
Yeah.
And since you're a halfling, you have to roll twice a one, right?
All right.
10% damage.
I don't get a sneak attack.
You do.
Oh, yeah, I do.
29.
All right.
Zephyr, you're up.
Remember, he hasn't yet attacked, so you get your assassin's advantage.
Too far for me to attack him.
I mean, you could use your arranged weapon.
Yeah.
I'll do that.
My pistol.
That's why I roll natural ones.
So nice.
Okay.
Second attack?
I can't see your die rolls, so just tell me what you rolled.
I rolled a 19.
Okay.
And then one damage.
Don't forget you get your bonuses
as an assassin.
56.
Yes, and there's an assassination bonus.
Oh, wait.
Yeah.
Let me find that.
Plus 19.
Roll in total 30 damage.
30 damage.
31 damage total.
31.
All right.
Okay.
Ghoul still thinks you're tasty food.
Marches up to Calmer.
Let's see what happens.
Okay.
So.
All right.
Okay.
So that's your start your turn.
So this doesn't start your turn.
Alright, so the ghoul attacks me up.
Okay, so he takes a bite on Calmer.
Why doesn't it know how to like do attacks?
Okay, so D20.
Oh, that is an attack.
Oh, I haven't ruled for damage.
Okay, that's a that definitely hits Calmer.
And Calmer takes 21 points of damage.
And must make a saving throw.
What is his saving throw against DC10 Constitution?
And what happens?
It's 7, so he's poisoned.
He's knocked out.
He is.
What is he?
Paralyzed.
So Calmer is paralyzed.
Alright.
The creature takes a swipe at Sequioa.
What's your armor class, Sequioa?
My armor class is
15.
Sorry.
Okay, roll the saving throw.
What saving throw?
Constitution, DC10.
DC10.
Not 20.
You are not paralyzed.
Alright, but you still take damage.
Eight points of damage.
Me?
Yeah, 8 points of damage.
Okay, the creature steps over, pushes, steps over Calmer, and attacks, I guess, Zinnia with his claw.
Zinnia, what's your armor class?
8.
Alright, that is a miss.
Hold on.
Calmer has a ring of evasion.
Rings of evasion have important properties.
Ring of reaction.
So that magic.
No, unfortunately, it's not magic.
It's an ability.
All right.
Zinnia, you're up.
I'll attack, I guess.
Okay.
What's armor class?
Its armor class is 14.
Oh, hold on.
Roll a constitution saving throw.
Constitution saving throw?
Yep.
23.
Natural 20.
All right.
You notice that it stinks a lot and that that stench has caused, well, it would have poisoned you, but your mask and your training as a spy allowed you to escape it just in time.
Yep.
All right.
Or more to the point.
You've smelled and tasted worse things in your life.
All right.
Do your attacks?
I did 19 points of damage.
All right.
How many hit points is you still have?
65.
I'll use a bonus.
All right.
I do 21 more points of damage.
So 40.
21 points for damage.
Alright.
Calmer needs to roll a saving throw.
See if he's not still paralyzed.
He's still paralyzed.
Sequioa, you're up.
First roll a saving throw against its stench.
The constitution?
You blow it.
So you have the poisoned condition, which means you need to roll it.
You roll with this advantage.
Great.
How much HP did the thing have left?
How much HP?
44?
The 15 hit?
15.
You just.
Let me just see.
Yes, it does hit, in fact.
Alright, I still have this advantage, though.
Damn it.
14.
Yeah, so yeah, you don't get your sneak attack bonus.
All right.
And I miss.
You missed.
All right.
No, both of those attacks hit.
15 and a 14.
It has an armor cost of 14.
31 points of damage.
Total?
Yeah, on that attack.
Well, no, you don't get your sneak attack bonus because you're attacking with disadvantage.
Is that really how it works?
Yes.
Let me just make sure.
Hold on.
Let me just check.
You just, you just.
I actually don't know.
Does sneak attack work if you have disadvantage?
No, yeah, it does not work if you have disadvantage.
All right.
So how much time?
How much?
11?
That's my dagger.
I have to roll one up.
I have to roll one more time, sorry.
Yeah, hit.
For 20 in total.
20 in total?
So you did.
Great.
24.
All right.
Can we build 20 points of damage, please?
Got 24.
All right.
Zephyr, you're up.
He's gonna die now.
All right.
First roll is saving throw.
Dexterity, what is it?
Constitutional poison.
Roll the 13.
All right, you are not poison.
You are poisoned.
I'm poisoned.
Yes, you are poisoned.
That's great.
Do I have disadvantage?
Yeah, disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls.
What do you have?
Advantage and disadvantage.
It cancels out.
Okay.
And just in case you're all wondering, it is not Magic the Gathering rules.
One disadvantage, one advantage.
They don't keep flipping until you make a decision.
Okay.
If you play Magic the Gathering, you have these spells where you keep dropping cards until we find, like, you know, there's a stack of 30 cards and then you figure out what the hell happened.
It's been too long since I played.
Yeah, apparently.
All right.
Okay.
So you have disadvantage.
So I rolled it 26.
But do I still have sneak attack?
Nope.
That's what we just established.
Ah, okay.
I rolled 26 to hit.
Did you roll it with disadvantage?
Yeah, no, with nothing.
Ah, okay.
26, yes.
Okay.
That is a hit.
It is Armor Class 14.
And I rolled 9 damage.
All right.
Alrighty.
The ghoul.
Ghoul is still alive.
Barely still alive.
All right.
It attempts to bite Sequioa and misses.
It strikes with its claws and misses.
All right.
And strikes with its claws again.
Wow.
Wow, I rolled some.
Minus or minus two.
All right, doesn't matter.
All of these would have missed.
Okay.
The ghoul.
Ghoul miss.
Zinnia.
You're up.
Constitution check, maybe?
No, because you made it, you are immune to ghoul, the ghoul poison until later.
Until after your next long rest.
What's this armor class again?
14.
And it had 9 points of damage.
9 points of damage.
Alright.
Okay.
Is that it?
Ultimate bonus.
I do 9 more points of damage.
18.
Alright.
He's dead.
Yes.
You search his body,
I presume.
Let me just make sure there's something that happens here.
All right.
You find a note on the corpse.
Yes.
Addressed to the four of you.
Really?
Yes.
Saying something saying, and it says, to the interlopers and thieves of my home.
Thank you for this harvest of death.
I shall, even if this creature doesn't kill you, eventually, one of them will.
We're being attacked.
You make roll a roll insight or investigation check.
Calmer rolls with a D20 plus 11.
Irl 21.
All right.
You remember something very interesting all of a sudden, Zinnia.
Oh, natural 20.
All right.
Zinnia and okay, so here's what you immediately figure out.
Zinnia remembers that Romag muttered that the undead on the first level no longer reported to him.
That somehow, remember how you guys went and fought all these undead?
That all of, you know, Romag was bitching about how they no longer reported to him and they no longer listened to him?
What that implies is they used to listen to somebody.
Yes.
And that what Zephyr has figured out is that that somebody may have been allied with Barkinar.
Remember, Barkinar was the old head of the Temple of Elemental Evil.
Earth.
He gets promoted to the upper temple, right?
Romag becomes the new head of the Earth Temple.
Right?
Hartsch becomes his number two.
You guys killed both of them, right?
Where's Barkinar?
Well, Barkinar is down in the bottom levels.
He's the one who's given you the homework assignments.
Right.
Well, it turns out now you're beginning to realize there was somebody else who could have had the job that Romag had.
And that somebody else is a necromancer.
Where is it?
There's a new Earth Temple guy?
No, so again, here's what you figure out.
Barkinar used to be the head of the Earth Temple.
He gets promoted to the Upper Temple.
Romag fills his job.
When you guys show up in the temple, Romag's the current head of the Earth Temple.
As you guys went around, you know, working for Romag, you defeated a whole bunch of undead creatures.
Do you remember that?
One of the things you remember is that Romag said, damn it, the ghouls and zombies and undead no longer listen to him.
At the time, you kind of were like, yeah, whatever.
Now you realize that when Romag got promoted, there was somebody else who worked for the Earth Temple.
It was appointed by Barkinar.
You don't know.
It was like maybe Romag didn't clean up his own mess.
Maybe Romag took the job and the necromancer escaped.
Who knows?
But that necromancer who was the old thought the job belonged to him now thinks that you guys don't deserve the job.
And you've basically created a dumpster fire of dead bodies for him to create and continuously attack you with.
We will have to be on our toes.
Right.
That's the important point.
So like there was a, and he's now basically, he's now arrogant enough to have dropped the note, put a note on one of his creations
telling you that, you know, if you find this note, let it be known that you aren't qualified to be the head of the Earth Temple.
It goes on, as Calmer picks up the note and goes, my God, this person's busy.
It goes on to describe how Calmer is a disgrace and that he's not qualified to be the head of the Earth Temple and that, you know, he can see through him and his approach to the rituals is all wrong.
Oh, we'll find this guy somehow.
Yes.
Something for you guys to keep in mind.
All right.
Okay.
So there is a, you know, as I said, being the big bad at the end of the game is a little bit painful because there's lots of other big bads.
All right.
Which way do you want to go?
South?
Well, that's pretty much the only way you haven't explored yet.
Or through the door over here to the east.
South, yes.
South?
Okay, so there's a door over here.
Would you like to open it?
Okay.
Alrighty.
Okay, let's see what's in this room.
All right.
This oddly shaped chamber is bisected by a curving wall of well-dressed bordered stones.
The wall is about four feet tall, and to the south of it is water, high enough to almost flow over the top.
Water trickles in from several places along the east, south, and west walls.
Overflow gravitates so the floor drains even as you watch.
Zephyr, you immediately recognize this for what it is, the water supply of the temple.
Or rather, the upper temple.
Of course, Calmer observes that the last time you thought you found a water supply turned out to be a creature from hell.
So we go in.
Ask your friend Calmer's light game.
The rest of you have to make a decision.
Sequioa?
Yeah, sure.
All right.
Zephyr, you walk in.
Amazingly, no creature, nothing attacks you.
It's just cold, wet water.
All right.
As you step on the...
Okay, roll an investigation check, Zephyr, before you step in.
Sorry.
Zephyr?
Yes.
Roll investigation?
Terrible roll, sorry.
Eight.
All right.
Okay.
So what happens is you slip and you slide and hit the wall over here.
So you're kind of, you've been knocked prone.
You look around, you look around and you realize that the floor is covered with a barely visible form algae, quite slimy and slippery.
And you also realize that the floor was sloping down.
It was barely visible.
But that's why you ended up sliding all the way down.
All right.
What do the rest of you do?
Let's go.
Zephyr, what do you do?
Sorry, Zinnia.
Sequioa, sorry, Sequioa.
Nick, what do you do?
So just to recap, Zephyr stepped on the.
He walked in the door.
All right.
I'm going to, if you're going to get in the water supply, I'm going to kind of just take a few steps back.
You're taking a few steps, but you're like, I've jumped into acidic pools one too many times.
All right.
Calmer calmly takes a rope and throws it to Zephyr.
I grabbed that.
All right.
Zinnia, what do you do?
Let Calmer handle it.
You're going to let Calmer handle it?
All right.
Zephyr, you've got a rope.
I'll pull my way to safety.
Do you want to look in the left?
Do you want to look at the...
By the way, remember, there was a four-foot wall, right?
That was holding as the water falls over.
It is just water.
Do you want to look inside?
Okay, let's take a peek.
You're going to take a peek.
All righty.
I'm going to take a peek.
You take a peek.
All right.
You see a large round slime-covered object.
I reach in the slime.
Well, it's like over, like you'd have to jump into the water
and swim down to there.
Okay, I'll jump in with a rope.
All right.
You tie yourself and jump in with the rope.
Okay.
So you're now sitting.
You're now in the water.
Okay.
Unfortunately, you know how to swim, so that's good to know.
And you're not exactly weighed down, so you're able to float.
Do you want to take a dive into the water to see what's in there?
Yeah.
You're going to take a deep breath and go there?
All right.
You take a deep breath, and you discover there is a shield that is covered in slime on slime.
Okay.
Do you want to try to pick it up?
Yeah, pick it up.
All right.
Roll a sleight of hands or a strength check, whichever one you want.
Sleight of hands.
Terrible rolls.
11.
The sleight of hand fails.
All right.
You're running out of air, so I presume you're going to reach up to the surface.
Do you want to try again?
Again, let's go.
You're going to try again.
All right.
Roll another sleight of hands.
But as you go in, you realize your last one caused it to be just dislodged enough so that if you miss again, you'll lose whatever it is, whatever's there.
It's become a little bit more tricky.
So roll again.
Come on.
13.
Oh, you made it just barely.
You made it just barely.
Grabbing onto the shield, you pull hard, it dislodges from the floor, and you're able to bring it up.
All right.
You swim to the surface, and all right, Calmer, and you.
Is anybody going to help Calmer?
Are you guys going to just rely on Calmer's strength to pull him forward?
You're going to go help him?
All right, because you help him, no more checks are required, and you manage to acquire a magical shield plus one.
So, does anybody need a shield?
Shield?
Okay, so you have a cleric who can use shields.
He goes, very well done.
That was very well done.
I cannot stress it much.
Calmer is very happy that you've managed to get him a new shield.
No worries, Calmer.
I'm here for you.
He knows.
He's very happy.
All right.
Okay.
Just very much that one.
All right.
Okay.
And we will stop here for today.
But there was one more thing I wanted to have happen today.
Oh, that's good.
We're good.
All right.
Well done.
There was one more thing that I should tell you that I forgot to tell you.
Since you did not kill the Minotaur, that was my bad.
All right.
Oh, the Minotaur.
One of the things you realized that the Minotaur, as it was mumbling to you, right, had seen the undead creatures you guys are talking about.
Like some of the bandits it was referring to, you now realize were undead.
So he can eat the undead.
Yeah, but it prefers fresh meat to undead meat.
You know,
seven innocent children from a remote city are preferable, but you know, you can't, beggars can't be pickers.
That's true.
All right, folks.
So yes, there is a necromancer who apparently feels that you owe him a job.
Okay.
All right.
All right, guys.
I hope you enjoyed yourselves.
I enjoyed myself.
See you next week, I hope.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
Good night.